Hamza Imam

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

© Karachi, Pakistan +92 309 2745394 | hamzaimam14@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamza-imam14/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated Junior SQA Engineer with more than 1 year of experience. Eager to contribute to the company's success in ensuring top-notch software quality. Proven track record in executing effective testing strategies, identifying defects, and enhancing overall project performance. Excited to bring my dedication and skills to your team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science Bahria University Karachi Campus

Feb 2020 - Jan 2024

CGPA - 3.42 **A Levels**

Whales College, Karachi

2017 - 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Reboot Technologies (TRAFIX LLC)

Software Quality Assurance Engineer (Tier 1)

Mar 2024 - Present

- Developing and reviewing test cases and scenarios.
- Writing Release Notes and QA Documentation.
- Smoke Testing for new features.
- Performing Regression to validate changes and fixes.
- Evaluating and Reproducing bugs reported by the Clients.
- Tracking and Managing bugs and development through Azure DevOps

Invention and Innovation

Aug 2023 - Mar 2024

Jr. Software Quality Assurance Engineer

- Performing manual testing for Websites and Mobile Applications.
- Performing automated runner through Newman.
- Performing API testing using scripts through Postman.
- Tracking project progress using Trello.
- Working closely with the design team to create an attractive UI.
- Bug reporting and documentation.
- Performing smoke and regression testing to validate software limitations.

PROJECTS

Foodnauts: A Restaurant Recommendation Platform (FYP)

- A Python/JS based Web App for discovering and searching local restaurants.
- Created the Python model and worked with the developers to validate changes and test different modules by Manual, Regression, Functional and UI Testing.

CYFyents

- An NFC based cashless events mobile application.
- Worked closely with the developers to find bugs, create logics and verify statistics and records.

TRAFIX OMS & RMS

- A Global Trading Software designed for fact paced real-time Trade Execution and Stock Exchange.
- Broker Friendly Fintech solution with RMS capabilities.
- Reproducing bugs and performing Smoke and Regression Testing to ensure a bug free software.

Skills

- API Testing
- UI/UX Testing
- Mobile Application Testing
- Website Testing
- Manual Testing
- Smoke Testing
- Regression Testing
- Functional Testing
- Requirement Analaysis
- Bug Reporting
- Postman Scripts

Tools

- Trello
- Zendesk
- Azure DevOps
- Postman
- Newman

Soft Skills

- Team Collaboration
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Team Communication
- Adaptability
- Analytical Thinking

Certifications

- QA Fundamentals (10Pearls University)
- API Testing using JMeter (10Pearls University)
- Information Security (10Pearls University)